George Brandon Saul Papers
George Brandon Saul Papers
- Manuscripts and published works (1968 additions)
  - Book reviews
    - of Saul's The Wild Queen, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Hound and Unicorn, 1966; collected verse, typescript carbon, revised (Box 1)
    - October Sheaf, 1965; publicity material only (Box 1)
    - Withdrawn in Gold, 1968; essays, incomplete typescript revised (Box 1)
  - Monographs
    - "Seumas O'Kelly", typescript carbon, revised (Box 1)
  - Musical compositions
    - "Autumn prelude", repro. of ms. (Box 1)
      See also "Prelude in E flat"
    - "Diversion", 1968; original rough ms. and repro. (Box 1)
    - "4th impromptu", ms. and repro. (Box 1)
    - "From an old mss.", 1918; 1968; based on "Warrior's scene," ms. and repro. (Box 1)
    - "Prelude in E flat", 1918; 1968; original ms. and revisions (Box 1)
      See also "Autumn prelude"
    - "Skeleton's jig", ms and repro. (Box 1)
    - "Summer etude", ms and repro. (Box 1)
    - "Valse: summer evening", rough ms. and repro. (Box 1)
  - Novellas
    - Liadain and Curither: a love story, holograph and original typescript, revised (Box 1)
  - Poems
    - "At my desk", 1968 (Box 1)
    - "Bovine elegy", holograph and original typescript (Box 1)
    - "On reading a medieval romance", 1967 (Box 1)
    - "Resurgence", 1968 (Box 1)
- Correspondence (1969 additions)
  See also Correspondence (1966-1967 accessions) and Correspondence (1968 additions)
  - 1968-1969 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia (1969 additions)
  - High school notebooks, Latin & forestry, ca. 1920 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of Saul (Package 1)
- Writings (1969 additions)
  Manuscripts and published works (1968 additions)
  - Book Reviews
    - A Commentary an the Collected Poems of W. B. Yeats by A. Norman Jeffries, 1969; Draft A, Draft B (Box 1)
    - The Development of William Butler Yeats: 1885-1900 by Harold Orel, 1969; tsc anno., 2 p.; also published version in Eire-Ireland, A Journal of Irish Studies, IV, 1 (Spring, 1969), 152-153. (Box 1)
    - In the Middle of the Fields by Mary Lavin, 1969; Draft A, holo. rev., 2 p.; Draft B, tsc anno., 2 p. (Box 1)
    - Sean O'Faolain by Paul A. Doyle, 1969; Draft A, holo. rev., 2 p.; Draft B, tsc anno., 2 p. (Box 1)
    - Yeats at Work by Curtis B. Bradford, July 1969; holo. notes; Draft A, holo. rev., 2 p.; Draft B, tsc anno., 3 p. (Box 1)
    - Sean O'Faolain and Yeats at Work, 1969; published material, Eire-Ireland, IV, 3 (Autumn, 1969), pp. 121-122, 127-128 (Box 1)
    - Yeats's Autobiography/Life as Symbolic Pattern by Joseph Ronsley, July 1969; Draft A, holo, rev.,, 1 p.; Draft B, tsc anno., 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Books
    - Carved in Findruine: Tales out of Irish Tradition, 1969?; ts, pt. mat. rev., 100 p. (Box 1)
    - Concise Introduction to Types of Literature in English, incomplete repro. page proof, rev.; index, tsc rev., 6 p. (Box 1)
    - Hound and Unicorn: Collected Verse--Lyrical, Narrative, and Dramatic., 1969; incomplete draft, holo., ts rev. ts rev., pp. 1-227; pub. mat., Philadelphia: The Walton Press, anno. & auto (Box 1)
    - A Little Book of Strange Tales, July, 1964; ts, tsc, pt. mat. rev., 34p. (Box 2)
    - Rushlight Heritage: Reflections on Selected Irish Short-Story Writers of the Yeatsian Era, 1969; ts, tsc rev., Sections 1-10 and Appendices; pub. mat., Philadelphia: The Walton Press (Box 2)
    - Unimagined Rose, ca. 1937; page proofs rev., (Box 2)
    - Withdrawn in Gold: Three Commentaries on Genius ( Studies in General and Comparative Literature, VI), June 1968; December 1969; tsc rev., 40 p.; page proof rev., 40 p. (Box 2)
  - Musical Scores
    - "Ramblings", Spring 1969; holo. rev., anno., 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "Theme in Search of Title,", December, 1968; Draft A, holo. rev., 1 p.; Draft B, repro. holo., 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "Toward New Year's", January 1969; Draft A, holo. rev., 1 p.; Draft B, repro. holo., 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Plays
    - The Trial by Fable: A One-Act Play, 1969; tsc; originally written in 1942; this revision for Hound and Unicorn (Box 2)
  - Poems
    - "Personal", 1969; ts rev., 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "Personal" and "Croagh", Spring, Summer, 1969; published material: The Dublin Magazine, VIII, 1 & 2, 44. (Box 2)
    - "To His Piano", Winter, 1969; pub. mat., Arizona Quarterly, XXV, 4, 318. (Box 2)
  - Radio Broadcast
    - "A. E. Coppard and His Forthcoming Volume, Cherry Ripe," on Station WTIC, October 19, 1935; tsc rev., 4 p. (Box 2)